Guide to the Jewish Community Relations Council, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1928-1959 AIS.1965.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Jewish Community Relations Council of Pittsburgh, Pa. Records
1928-1959
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Jewish Community Relations Council (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1965.11
10.625 Linear Feet (20 boxes)
The Jewish Public Relations Council was an organization designed to deal with the problems inherent in the relationships between Jews and all other religions and races. The records in this collection include correspondence, reports, periodicals, and pamphlets of extremist groups and individuals, largely anti-semitic, for the period 1935-1950.
Scope and Content Notes
The Jewish Public Relations Council was designed to deal with the problems inherent in the relationships between Jews and all other religions and races. Through the 1930s, 1940s, and 1950s the Jewish Public Relations Council collected materials from groups and organizations promoting fascism, race-hating, and anti-semitism. This collection contains four series - Series I contains correspondence, reports, periodicals, and pamphlets of organizations, largely anti-semitic. Series II contains subject files on discrimination and anti-semitic individuals. Series III contains periodicals based on racial discrimination. Series IV contains publications including books, journals, reports, and pamphlets from anti-semitic and racially prejudiced individuals and organizations; subjects include anti-semitism, civil rights, discriminations, Nazism, subversive organizations, Father Coughlin, and Gerald K. Smith.
Arrangement
Series I. Organization, 1936-1951
Series II. Subject Files, 1930-1963
Series III. Periodicals, 1928-1963
Series IV. Publications
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
A gift from the Jewish Community Relations Council, Pittsburgh Chapter, June 7, 1965.
Previous Citation
Jewish Community Relations Council Records, 1928-1959, AIS.1965.11, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Jewish Community Relations Council, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania Records, 1928-1959, 65:11, Archives of Industrial Society, University of Pittsburgh Libraries
Social action; Ethnic groups; Associations; Radicalism -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Discrimination -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Civil rights -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Jews -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Smith, Gerald L. K. (Gerald Lyman Kenneth); Jewish Community Relations Council (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward)
- Organizations, 1936-1951; I.
  - America First Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - America First Party, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Boycott Against Aggressor Nations, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Civil Liberties Union. Pittsburgh Chapter, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Council on Public Affairs, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Boycott Against Aggressor Nations, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American League to Combat Anti-Semitism, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Prophetic League, Inc., 1942 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - America's First, ca. 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Anti-Defamation League, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Appreciate America, Inc., 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Belgian Information Center, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Children's Crusade for Children, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Christian Nationalist Crusade, No Date (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Citizenship Educational Service, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Common Council for American Unity, 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Committee for National Morale, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Committee for the Defense of America's Constitutional Rights, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding Allies, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Council for Democracy, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Czechoslovak National Council of America, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Descendants of American Revolution, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Deutscher Konsum-Verbund, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Draft MacArthur for President of the United States, No Date (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Educational Policies Commission, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Fair Rent Committee, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Friends of Democracy, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fight for Freedom Committee, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - German American Bond, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - German American Congress for Democracy, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - German Library of Information, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Humanity Guild, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Institute of Jewish Affairs, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - International Coordination Council, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - International Free World Association - Pittsburgh Branch, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - International Workers Order, No Date (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1942-1945 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Jewish Peoples Committee, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Knights of the White Camellia, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Knights of Young India, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - League for Human Rights, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - League for Industrial Democracy, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - National Committee on the Cause and Cure for War, No Date (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - New York City Coordinating Committee for Democratic Action, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Non-Sectarian Anti-Nazi League to Champion Human Rights, Inc., 1940-1943 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Public Affairs Association of Pittsburgh, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Selfhelp of Emigres from Central Europe, Inc., 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Service Bureau of Intercultural Education, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - State Council for a Pennsylvania FEPC, 1940-1942 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Workers' Defense League, No Date (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - World Citizens Association, 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Subject File, 1930-1963; II.
  - Allport, Gordon W., No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Anti-Black Prejudice, 1943-1957 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Anti-Nazism, 1930-1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Anti-Nazism Propaganda, 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Anti-Semitism, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Anti-Semitism/German Propaganda, 1938-1941 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Semitism/U.S, 1938-1946 (Box 5, Folder 7-9)
  - Anti-Semitism/Catholic Opinion, No Date (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Civil Rights, 1945-1953 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Civil Rights, 1942-1950 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Civil Rights, 1948-1953 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Civil Rights, 1944-1959 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Church/State/School, 1941-1958 (Box 6, Folder 4-6)
  - Cole, Reverend Walton E., 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Community Reports/Anti-Defamation League, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Democracy, 1938-1950 (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
  - Defense, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Dies Committee, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Discrimination (Careers), 1939-1948 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Discrimination (Housing), 1951 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Father Coughlin, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 8-10)
  - Radio Addresses, 1939-1940 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Fair Employment, 1943-1953 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - Foreign Agents, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Foreign Language Press, Western Pennsylvania, Report, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - German Publications, 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Intercultural Education, 1944-1951 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Intercultural Education, 1945-1962 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Intercultural Education, 1940-1960 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Intercultural Education, 1941-1952 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Veterans, 1942-1946 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - KKK, Western Pennsylvania, 1941-1944 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Legislation (Aliens and Immigration), 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Lindbergh, Charles, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Marston, Horace M., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Nazi Publications, 1935-1937 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Nazis and Jews, 1939-1940 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Negro Anti-Semitism, 1940-1942 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Pelley, William, 1939-1940 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Planned Economy, 1939 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Pro-Jewish material, 1939-1942 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Propaganda/Anti-Semitic, 1936-1939 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Race Relations, 1939-1961 (Box 10, Folder 7-8)
  - Refugees, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Smith, Gerald K., 1936-1941 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Smith, Gerald K., 1943 (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
  - Smith, Gerald K., 1944 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Smith, Gerald K., 1945 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Smith, Gerald K., 1946 (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
  - Smith, Gerald K., 1947-1951 (Box 11A, Folder 1)
  - Subversive Organizations, 1940-1942 (Box 11A, Folder 2)
  - Sullivan, E.F., No Date (Box 11A, Folder 3)
  - Tukacs, Rev. George, 1940 (Box 11A, Folder 4)
  - United Nations, 1943-1958 (Box 11A, Folder 5-7)
  - Wilkie, Wendell, 1940 (Box 11A, Folder 8)
  - Winrod, Rev. Gerald, 1939 (Box 11A, Folder 9)
- Periodicals, 1928-1963; III.
  - A.D.L. Review, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Action, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Der Adler, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - America in Danger, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - America Speaks no. 1, No Date (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - American Action v. I, no. 1, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - The American Teacher, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - The American Vindicator v. I, no. 2, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Anti Defamation League. Bulletin, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Anti Defamation League. Newsletter, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - The Anti-Nazi Bulletin, 1939-1940 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Appeal to Reason v. I, no. 5, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - The Beacon Light, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Blackshirt v. I, no. 4-5, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Boycott Bulletin, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - The Broom v. IX, no. 29, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Changing World September, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Christian Free Press, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Consolation, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - The Cross and the Flag, vol. 1-2, 1942-1943 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - The Cross and the Flag, vol. 3-4, 1941-1946 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - The Cross and the Flag, vol. 5, 1946-1947 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - The Cross and the Flag, vol. 6, 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - The Cross and the Flag, vol. 7, 1948-1949 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - The Cross and the Flag, vol. 8, 1949-1950 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - The Cross and the Flag, vol. 9, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - The Cross and the Flag, vol. 21-22, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - The Defender Magazine, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Deutscher Weckruf und Beobachter, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Direction, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Equality I II, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Facts in Review, 1939-1941 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
  - Facts vs. Fiction I II, 1940-1941 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Fair Employment - Pa., 1950-1951 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Friends of Democracy's Battle v. 5-8, 1947-1950 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - The Home Front II., 1946 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Inside German Reports no.2-25, 1939-1943 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - In Re: Germany I-IV, 1941-1944 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Items of Interest in the Congressional Record, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Jewish Affairs v. 1 no. 5-13, 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Digest, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Judischen Gemeiden in Bohmen und Mahren zu Prag. Rat. Informationsbulletin, 1958-1959 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Judischen Gemeiden in Bohmen und Mahren zu Prag. Rat. Informationsbulletin, 1941-1946 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Judischen Gemeiden in Bohmen und Mahren zu Prag. Rat. Informationsbulletin, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The Letter, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
  - The Letter, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - The Letter, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - The Letter, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - The Letter, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The Letter, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Letter, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Liberation, 1928-1939 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - National American, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - People and Freedom, 1941-1942 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - The Pittsburgh News-letter 1941 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - The Propaganda Battlefront 1-4, 1944-1946 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Protestant Digest, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Sozialdemokratischer Informations Brief, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Social Justice, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - The Thunderbolt, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Tri-State American v. I, no. 1-2 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - The Voice for Human Rights, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - L'unita del popolo I II, 1940-1941 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - World Jewish Congress, Bulletin, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - World Service 1-6, 1934-1939 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Publications, 1930-1959; IV.
  - Publications, by Author, A-C (Box 18)
    - Agar, William M. Food or Freedom: the Vital Blockade; New York, Farrar Rinehart, (America In A World at War #13), c1941; 1.
    - Agar, William M. Where Do Catholics Stand?; New York, Farrar Rinehart, (America in a world at war #4), c1941; 2.
    - Alpenfels, Ethel J. Sense and Nonsense about Race; New York, Friendship Press, 1946; 3.
    - American Association for Jewish Education. Community Responsibility for Jewish Education; New York, c1940; 4.
    - American Association for the United Nations. The United Nations Report #1: The London Session; New York, 1936; 5.
    - American Association for the United Nations. We, the Peoples: A Brief History of the United Nations; New York: Education Committee for School and College Activities, 1947; 6.
    - American Association for the United Nations. United Nations and You; New York: American Association for the United Nations Education Department, 1947; 7.
    - American Friends of German Freedom. Norway Does Not Yield: The Story of the First Year.; New York, 1941; 7a.
    - American Jewish Committee. Jewish Post-War Problems: A Study Course; New York: Research Institute on Peace and Post-War Problems, 1942; 8.; 8 Volumes
    - American Jewish Committee. Post-War Migrations: Proposal for an International Agency.; New York: Research Institute on Peace and Post-War Problems, 1943; 9.
    - American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee. Aid to Jews overseas: Report on Activities; New York, 1939; 10.
    - Black, John D., Sir Willmott Lewis, Clarence E. Peckett. America's Food and Europe's Needs; Philadelphia: The American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1941; 10a.
    - Anti-Defamation League. Americans All; Chicago, (Fireside Discussion Group Pamphlet #32), undated; 11.
    - Balderston, John L. Chicago Blueprint; New York: The American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1943; 12.
    - Benedict, Ruth (Fulton). The Races of Mankind; New York: Public Affairs Committee (Public Affairs Pamphlet #85), 1946; 13.
    - Benet, Stephen Vincent. A Summons to the Free; New York: Farrar Rinehart, (America In a World at War. #6), 1940; 14.
    - Benet, Stephen Vincent. They Burned the Books; New York: Farrar Rinehart, c.1942; 15.
    - Bernays, Edward L. Speak up for Democracy; New York: Viking, 1940; 16.
    - Biddle, Francis. Democracy and Racial Minorities; New York: Institute for Religious Studies, 1943; 17.
    - Bone, Hugh A. "Smear" Politics: An Analysis of 1940 Campaign Literature; Washington, D.C.: American Council on Public Affairs, 1941; 18.
    - Britt, George. The Fifth Column Is Here; New York: Wilfred Funk, c1940; 19.
    - Britt, George. Rumors (Made in Germany); New York: N.Y.: Council for Democracy, 1942; 20.
    - Brookings Institution. Suggested Standards for Determining Un-American Activities; Washington, D.C., 1945; 21.
    - Bureau on Jewish Employment Problems. Employment Barriers in Wartime; Chicago, 1942; 22.
    - Bureau of Jewish Employment Problems. Some Aspects of Employment Discrimination: An American Problem; Cleveland, 1941; 23.
    - Church, John Merrick. B'nai B'rith; New York, undated; 24.
    - Citizenship Educational Service. Footprints of the Trojan Horse: Some Methods Used by Foreign Agents Within the United States; New York, 1940; 24a.
    - Citron, W.M., ed. Aufbrau Almanac: The Immigrant's Handbook; New York: German-Jewish Club, 1941; 25.
    - Claessens, August. Race Prejudice; New York: Rand School, c1943; 26.
    - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, Committee of Human Rights. Draft International Bill of Human Rights; New York, 1947; 27.
    - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace. The United Nations and Non-self Governing Peoples: A Plan for Trustreeship; New York,., 1944; 28.
    - Commission to Study the Organization of Peace. Uniting the Nations for Health; New York, No Date; 29.
    - Common Council for American Unity. The World We Fight For and American Unity; New York 19p. Addresses by Pearl S. Buck, Sir Norman Angell, Sigred Undset, Thomas Mann, Harold C. Urey, Otto Loeuvi at the Nobel Anniversary Dinner, 1942; 30.
    - Consultative Council of Jewish Organizations. International Protection of the Human Rights of Minorities; New York,., 1950; 31.
    - Council Against Intolerance in America. We're All Americans: Teacher's Manual No. 2; New York, 1942; 32.
    - Council for Democracy. Advance Through Crisis...; New York, 1941; 33.
    - Culbertson, Ely. Summary of the World Federation Plan; New York: World Federation, 1943; 34.
  - Publications, by Author, D-K (Box 19)
    - Desser, Hannah F. Here's the Way to Secure These Rights; Cincinnati: Woman's Division of Christian Service Board of Missions and Church Extension, undated; 35.
    - Di Lascia, Alfredo P. L'anti-semitismo e Un'eresia Christiana, undated; 36.
    - Eichelberger, Clark M. The United Nations Charter: What Was Done at San Francisco; New York, 1945; 37.
    - Eichelberger, Clark M. Time Has Come for Action; New York, 1944; 38.
    - Eichelberger, Clark M. UN: The First Ten Years; New York: Harper and Brothers, 1955; 39.
    - Embree, Edwin R. Peoples of the Earth; New York: Hinds, Hayden, and Eldrige, 1938; 40.
    - Farazo, Ladislas, ed. German Psychological Warfare: Survey and Bibliography; New York: Committee for National Morale, 1941; 41.
    - Field, Marshall. The Negro Press and the Issues of Democracy; Chicago: Speech delivered before the First Annual Dinner of the Crystal Press Club, 1944; 42.
    - Fisher, Lloyd H. The Problem of Violence: Observations on Race Conflicts in Los Angeles; San Francisco: American Council on Race Relations, circa 1945; 43.
    - Fredman, Joseph George. Brothers in Arms; New York: Jewish War Veterans of U.S., 1945; 44
    - Friedrich, Carl J. The Poison in Our System; New York: Council for Democracy, 1940; 45.
    - German Library of Information. Polish Acts of Atrocity Against the German Minority in Poland; New York, 1940; 46.
    - The Goood Neighbor Association, Committee on Propaganda Analysis. Instructions for Recognizing and Reporting Propaganda; Boston, 1940; 47.
    - Hall, Gordon D. The Hate Campaign Against the UN; Boston: The Beacon Press, circa 1952; 48.
    - Hamburger, Ludwig. How Nazi Germany Has Mobilized and Controlled Labor; Washington, D.C.: Brookings Institute, 1940; 49.
    - Haring, Douglas G. Racial Differences and Human Resemblances; Syracuse, circa 1947; 50.
    - Hartley, Livingston. It's Up to the Senate; New York: American Association for the United Nations, 1945; 51.
    - Hartshorne, E. Y. German Youth and the Nazi Dream of Victory; New York: Farrar Rinehart, (American In a World at War #12), 1941; 52.
    - Height, Dorothy I. Step by Step with Interracial Groups; New York: Woman's Press, 1948; 53.
    - Hoke, Henry. Blackmail; New York: Reader's Book Service, 1941; 54.
    - International Institute of Social Research. Report on Its History, Aims and Activities; New York, 1939; 55.
    - Ickes, Harold L. The Third Term Bugaboo: A Cheerful Anthology, 1940; 56.
    - Jewish Welfare Board. In Freedom's Cause; New York, (Jewish Information Series #3), 1943; 57.
    - Jones, J. Morris. Americans All, Immigrants All; Washington, D.C.: The Federal Radio Education Committee, undated; 58.
    - Kamp, Joseph P. The Fifth Column vs. The Dies Committee; New Haven, Conn.: Constitutional Educational League, 1941; 59.
    - Kamp, Joseph P. Native Nazi Purge Plot; New Haven, Conn.: Constitutional Educational League, 1942; 60.
    - Kamp, Joseph P. Vote CIO ... And Get a Soviet America; New York, 1944; 61.
    - Kellog, Paul, ed. Calling America; New York: Harper Brothers, circa 1930; 62.
    - Kral, Vaclav. Lesson from History: Documents Concerning Nazi Policies for Germanisation and Extermination in Czechoslovakia; Prague: Orbis, 1961; 63.
    - Kulterkamypf Association. The Church struggle in Germany: A Survey of Four Crucial Years; London, 1937; 64.
  - Publications, by Author, L-Z (Box 20)
    - League of Nations Association. Essential Facts: Underlying World Organization; New York, 1941; 65.
    - Lee, Irving J. Social Action: A Way with Prejudice; New York: Council for Social Action of the Congregational Christian Churches, 1942; 66.
    - Lerner, A. R. The March of Evil; New York: F.F.F. Publishers, 1945; 67.
    - Mayor's Conference on Race Relations. City planning in race relations; Chicago, (Proceedings of the Chicago Mayor's Conference on Race Relations), 1944; 68.
    - Meany, George. We Call All Men Brothers; New York, (Address delivered upon receipt of the Philip Murray award from the NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund), 1957; 69.
    - Methodist Church (U.S.). General Board of Education. Bridges of Brotherhood, circa 1947; 69a.
    - Methodist Church Board of Missions and Church Extensions, Women's Division of Christian Service. A Christian's Primer of the United Nations; Cincinnati, Ohio, 1950; 70.
    - Montreal Women's Anti-Communist League. The Key to the Mystery; Montreal, Canada, undated; 71.
    - Moody, Joseph. Why are Jews Persecuted?; St. Louis: The Queen's Work, 1938; 72.
    - Murphy, Frank. In Defense of Democracy; Washington, D.C.: American Council on Public Affairs, 1940; 73.
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People. American Rights for American Citizens; New York: NAACP, (41st Annual report), 1949; 74.
    - National Medical Fellowships. Negroes in Medicine; Chicago, 1952; 75.
    - National Council of American Soviet Friendship. The Book the Nazis Like; New York, 1945; 76.
    - Northrup, Herbert R. Will Negroes Get Jobs Now?; New York: Public Affairs Committee, (Public Affairs Pamphlet #110), 1945; 77.
    - Pennsylvania. Report of the Governor's Commission on Industrial Race Relations: Employment Practices in Pennsylvania; Harrisburg, Pa., 1957; 78.
    - Phillips, M. E. The Nazi, the Jew, the Christian; Chicago, circa 1940; 79.
    - Radio League of the Little Flower. American Answer to Father Coughlin's Critics; Royal Oak, Michigan, 1940; 80.
    - Rosenberg, James N. Declaration of Interdependence: Human Rights and the United Nations; New York: The National Conference of Christians and Jews,. (Human Relations Pamphlet #10), 1947; 81.
    - Scherman, Harry. A Philosophy of the War; New York, 1941; 82.
    - Schnapper, Morris Bartel, ed. Five Years of Hitler; New York: American Council on Public Affairs, circa 1938; 83.
    - Schnapper, Morris Bartel, ed. Heywood Broun; Washington, D.C.: American Council on Public Affairs, 1940; 84.
    - Schnapper, Morris Bartel. Youth Betrayed; New York: International Relief Association, undated; 85.
    - Seldes, George. The Facts Are: A Guide to Falsehood and Propaganda in the Press and Radio; New York: In Fact, 1942; 86.
    - Sheen, Fulton J. What Can I Do?; Washington, D.C.: National Council of Catholic Men, undated; 87.
    - Southern Conference for Human Welfare. The Poll Tax; Washington, D.C.: American Council on Public Affairs, undated; 88.
    - Southern Regional Council. Race in the News: Usage in Southern Newspapers; Atlanta, Ga., circa 1949; 89.
    - Spiegler, Samuel, et al. How Can Jews Survive the Present Crisis?; Cincinnati: Union of American Hebrew Congregations, 1943; 90.